avanishinfo@gmail.com

# Summary

Highly skilled technical lead software developer having 8 years of experience in microservices architecture and agile methodologies on Transport & e-commerce products and also Built core features for Android apps with 10 million+ downloads. A versatile team player, keen to learn new technology, and willing to take on dynamic responsibility.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Technologies: Spring Boot, Microserves, Spring Cloud, Amazon Web Services (AWS), Hibernate, Data JPA, JUnit, Restful Web Service, Google Api, Video Streaming, OpenCV, Android SDK, Firebase, MVVM, MVC, RxJava and more.
- Programming: Java, Kotlin.
- Database: My SQL, PostgreSQL, Room DB.
- Tools: JIRA, Jenkins, Git, Maven, Gradle, Postman, Eclipse, Android Studio

## **PROJECTS**

Project 1: Currently working on "Ministry of Road Transport and Highways - E-Challan"

Platform & Skills: Spring Boot, Rest Api, Java, JSON, Postgres DB

Link: https://echallan.parivahan.gov.in/index/accused-challan

Description: E-challan is an electronic traffic challan that is issued if you violate traffic rules and

regulations by committing traffic offences such as over-speeding, rash driving etc.

Role: Involved in Java backed coding.

Project 2: Maintanance of "Ministry of Road Transport and Highways - mParivahan App"

Platform & Skills: Spring Boot with microservices, Rest Api, Java, JSON, MySQL DB

Link: https://parivahan.gov.in/parivahan//en/content/mparivahan

**Description:** Provides Transport Service access to citizens through a mobile-based application.

Role: Involved in Java backed coding.

Project 3: Currently working on NexGen mParivahan Android App(10 million +)"

Platform & Skills: Spring Boot with microservices, Rest Api, Java, JSON, MySQL DB

Link: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.nic.mparivahan&hl=en\_IN

**Description:** Provides Transport Service access to citizens through a mobile-based application.

Role: Involved in Android & Kotlin coding to develop app UI and functionality

Project 4: Maintenance of "Ministry of Road Transport and Highways - eChallan Android App.

Platform & Skills: Android SDK, Java, AES, NDK, JSON Parsing, Payment gateway etc.

Link: Reserved Software for Traffic Police and Transport Police.(Not Open user based app)

**Description:** Provides Transport Service access to citizens through a mobile-based application.

Role: Involved in Android & Java coding to develop app UI and functionality

Project 5: Panini Keypad (Indian Innovation & Awarded with many country, Patent of US)

Platform & Skills: Java, Eclipse, Netbean

Link: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Panini Keypad

**Description:** It is an application that offers single key press input in Indian language on mobile. So

far, it supports Hindi, Bengali, Assamese, Kannada, Malayalam etc.

Role: Involved in Desktop Application & Mobile App Support coding to develop app UI and

functionality.

Project 6: Roman Panini Keypad (Phonetic Typing) (Desktop App and Android App both)

Platform & Skills: Android SDK, Java, Eclipse Link: <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Panini">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Panini</a> Keypad

Description: Roman Keypad allows you to write in Roman/English alphabets to write in an Hindi/

Indian language (Transliteration).

Role: Involved in coding and development of GUI.

Project 7: mCamApp:(Streaming, OpenCV)

Platform & Skills: Android SDK, Java, XML, JSON

Description: With the vCamapp, users can transmit video streams from their mobile devices to Other

Platform, Surveillance Station for live view and video recordings on the system.

Role: Involved in coding and development of GUI.

## **EXPERIENCE**

- Currently Working as a Tech Lead in Akal Information Systems Ltd, Delhi since Feb-2019.
- Worked at ZOTTO (CiboApp) Ltd from February 2017 to March 2018.
- Worked at Codefire Technology Pvt Ltd from March 2016 to January 2017.
- Worked at Luna Ergonomics Pvt Ltd. from September 2014 to March 2016.

## **EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATION**

• Master of Computer Application -2014